# Lisa Mabley

# Senior Full-Stack Software Engineer

lisamabley@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/lisamabley/ Website: lisamabley.github.io https://github.com/LisaMabley (612) 817-7516 Minneapolis, MN 55413

# **PROFILE**

Engineering leader and technical problem solver with over 7 years of full stack software engineering experience with *TypeScript, Node, PostgreSQL, React, Angular,* and *GCP*. Over 10 years of experience wearing many hats in small/early-stage startups. Nimble and quick to learn new frameworks. Exceptional collaboration, mentoring, teamwork, and communication skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Joyuus, Boston MN** - Founding Engineer

SEPT 2023 - PRESENT

- Spearheaded the establishment of the engineering team, developing and implementing robust processes and procedures from scratch.
- Played a pivotal role in shaping the company's technical vision, architecture, and roadmap, ensuring scalability and future growth.
- Championed the adoption of best practices and coding standards, maintaining high code quality and ensuring the team's continuous professional development.
- Led development of product MVP in preparation for clinical trial and public beta testing, including building and assessing roadmap timing and resources, as well as iterating based on user feedback and market needs.

Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis MN - Full-Stack Software Engineering TA MAY 2023 - AUG 2023

- Mentored students with little to no coding experience to entry-level software careers
- Demonstrated logging, debugging, and troubleshooting techniques
- Eased learning friction and removed blockers to progress. Modeled growth mindset

Cloudburst SBC, Minneapolis MN - Senior Full-Stack Software Developer MAY 2018 - APRIL 2023

 Built and scaled a public-facing mobile app, corporate CMS, and REST API for a senior living company with thousands of users and dozens of properties around the country; Created Integrated an IoT platform with fleet-managed devices; Released mobile apps to the Google Play store and iOS App Store; Prototyped an Amazon Alexa skill; Imported data from external systems.

TypeScript, React, Angular, Node, PostgreSQL, Ionic, Capacitor, GCP, AWS

- Enhanced a million-dollar yard care application project by adding customer data import, estimation functionality and a subcontractor layer, reducing manual work.
   TypeScript, React, Supabase, Node, Next.js, GCP
- Established baseline data analytics and KPI levels for a rapidly-growing telehealth client, revealing and correcting gaps in data collection. Created an admin dashboard to track and visualize employee performance and care standards for a large volume of patients.
   PostgreSQL, Big Query, Google Data Studio, GCP
- Scaled a training and compliance-focused client's applications from 2,000 users to over 44,000 users; Optimized REST API back-end service by streamlining queries and caching database results; Upgraded front-end app performance via table pagination, search, and sort; Released mobile apps to the Google Play store and iOS App Store.
   TypeScript, Angular, Node, Firebase, PostgreSQL, Ionic, GCP
- Created HIPAA-compliant logging system and client dashboard to track signup failures and abandons, allowing a healthcare client to optimize its account creation and health history input process, unlocking product improvements and onboarding insights.
   Sentry, Google Data Studio, GCP

ITM TwentyFirst, Minneapolis MN - Full-Stack Software Engineer
JUNE 2016 - MAY 2018

- Built a public-facing web app and REST API service for new customers to log in and confirm/update contact information, saving the company significant costs by automating a time-consuming step of customer interaction. TypeScript, Angular, Node, MS SQL Server
- Synthesized large datasets and wrote complex queries, functions, and stored procedures
  to isolate the financial products with the highest value, and provide clients with actionable
  information. MS SQL Server

Martin Williams Advertising, Minneapolis MN - Digital Production Artist OCTOBER 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2013

#### **EDUCATION**

**Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis, MN** - Full Stack Software Engineering Certificate Completed an 18-week immersive program in full-stack software engineering using JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, Express, and MySQL

## Minneapolis College, Minneapolis, MN

Took semester courses in *Python, Java, iOS,* and *Android* development.

**University of Minnesota – Twin Cities, Minneapolis, MN** - *Bachelor's Degree* Completed a liberal arts bachelor's degree program with a major in art.

# **SKILLS**

- Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS, Java, Python, Lua
- Frameworks: Angular, Node.js, NestJS, React.js, Express, Next.js
- Databases: PostgreSQL, Cloud Firestore, MySQL, SQL Server
- Data Tools: Google Data Studio, Big Query
- Cloud Platforms: GCP, Supabase, Firebase, AWS, Heroku
- Mobile Tools: Ionic, Cordova, Capacitor
- Testing Tools: Playwright, Mocha, Jest, Jasmine
- ORM: Prisma, TypeORM
- CI/CD: GitHub Actions
- Performance Monitoring: Sentry
- Dev Tools: GitHub, BitBucket, Jira, Docker, npm, Yarn, Homebrew, Asana, Notion
- Creative: Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)
- Methodologies: Agile

## **VOLUNTEER MENTORING**

- Prime Digital Academy (20 week program)
- Technovation Challenge (3 month program)
- Hack the Gap hackathon (annual single day events)
- Code Switch hackathon (annual single day events)
- CoderDojo Twin Cities (monthly single day events)
- Big Brothers Big Sisters Twin Cities (8+ year relationship)